const quizQuestions10en = [{
    question:"Regarding the welding electric arc, it is possible to state:",
    answers: ["To maintain itself, the arc receives heat from the weld pool and the superheated electrode tip.",
    "The arc receives heat from the overheated electrode tip and transmits it to the base metal.",
    "The electric arc is the passage of a large amount of electric current through an ionized atmosphere, between two electrodes subjected to an adequate potential difference.",
    "The consumption (melting rate) of the electrode in an electric arc process does not depend on the polarity of the current."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Why is alternating current (AC) used in aluminium TIG welding?",
    answers: ["Because the oxide layer on the surface of the aluminium does not allow current to pass in only one direction.",
    "Because magnetic arc blowing is very strong when welding aluminium with direct current (DC).",
    "Because the oxide layer is destroyed during the positive half-cycle and the tungsten electrode cools down during the negative half-cycle.",
    "Because the oxide layer is destroyed during the negative half-cycle and the tungsten electrode cools down during the positive half-cycle."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following gases would you use to weld with the MIG/MAG process with long arc and spray transfer?",
    answers: ["Mixtures containing argon and low amount of O2 (typically up to 5%) or low amount of CO2 (typically up to 15%).",
    "Pure CO2.",
    "Pure helium.",
    "Mixtures containing CO2 or O2 and a small amount of argon."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the use of shielding gases in MIG/MAG welding, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Increasing the shielding gas flow rate is always beneficial for improving weld quality, but it increases costs.",
    "The regulated value of the shielding gas flow rate depends on the wire diameter and current polarity.",
    "It is possible to reduce the consumption of shielding gas without impairing the quality of the weld by applying special techniques and devices in the gas supply system.",
    "One of the main advantages of using gas mixtures instead of pure gases is that they allow a better use of pure gases that are left over from other operations in the company."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the main advantage of using a mixture of inert and active gases with the MIG/MAG process when compared to using just one type of inert or active gas?",
    answers: ["Ar-CO2 mixtures produce less spatter compared to welding with pure CO2.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures with CO2 between 15% and 25% allow for spray and pulsed metal transfer, which are not feasible in pure Ar welding.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures offer better penetration profile compared to pure CO2 welding.",
    "The 50%Ar+50%CO2 mixture allows for higher welding speeds on heavy plate compared to welding with pure CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the main advantage of using a mixture of inert and active gases with the MIG/MAG process when compared to using just one type of inert or active gas?",
    answers: ["Ar-CO2 mixtures with CO2 between 15% and 25% allow for spray and pulsed metal transfer, which are not feasible in pure Ar welding.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures with less than 15% CO2 allow for both spray and pulsed metal transfer, which are not feasible when welding with pure CO2.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures offer better penetration profile compared to pure CO2 welding.",
    "The 50%Ar+50%CO2 mixture allows for higher welding speeds on heavy plate compared to welding with pure CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the main advantage of using a mixture of inert and active gases with the MIG/MAG process when compared to using just one type of inert or active gas?",
    answers: ["Ar-CO2 mixtures with CO2 between 15% and 25% allow for spray and pulsed metal transfer, which are not feasible in pure Ar welding.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures offer better penetration profile compared to pure CO2 welding.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures offer better penetration profile compared to pure Ar welding.",
    "The 50%Ar+50%CO2 mixture allows for higher welding speeds on heavy plate compared to welding with pure CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the main advantage of using a mixture of inert and active gases with the MIG/MAG process when compared to using just one type of inert or active gas?",
    answers: ["Ar-CO2 mixtures with CO2 between 15% and 25% allow for spray and pulsed metal transfer, which are not feasible in pure Ar welding.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures offer better penetration profile compared to pure CO2 welding.",
    "The 50%Ar+50%CO2 mixture allows for higher welding speeds on heavy plate compared to welding with pure CO2.",
    "Ar-CO2 mixtures with CO2 above 25% allow faster welding speeds on heavy plate compared to pure Ar welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment in the conventional MIG/MAG process, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To obtain wide beads and low penetration, it is recommended to use high tension and wire feed speed, in order to reach the spray transfer mode.",
    "\"Increasing the wire feed speed increases the current, but the arc length is reduced (if the distance \"\"contact tip - workpiece\"\" remains the same).\"",
    "the arc voltage affects the short circuit frequency: the higher the voltage, the higher this frequency;",
    "By adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit transfer can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment in the conventional MIG/MAG process, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To obtain wide beads and low penetration, it is recommended to use high tension and wire feed speed, in order to reach the spray transfer mode.",
    "the arc voltage affects the short circuit frequency: the higher the voltage, the higher this frequency;",
    "Low penetration welds can be obtained with low wire feed speed and low voltage, a condition that can cause an arc that generates low heat input.",
    "By adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit transfer can be obtained."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the adjustment in the conventional MIG/MAG process, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["To obtain wide beads and low penetration, it is recommended to use high tension and wire feed speed, in order to reach the spray transfer mode.",
    "By adjusting the wire feed speed and keeping the arc voltage high, the short-circuit transfer can be obtained.",
    "the arc voltage affects the short circuit frequency: the higher the voltage, the higher this frequency;",
    "For the same wire feed speed, the higher the voltage used, the longer the arc length, which leads to wider welds."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding MIG/MAG welding equipment and consumables, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["Push-pull torches are used for thicker electrode wires to help the feeder to propel them.",
    "Push-pull torches are used for softer electrode wires, such as aluminium, to prevent it from getting stuck inside the conduit (wire guide).",
    "Most MIG/MAG welding equipment comes from the factory with only one inductance value.",
    "The torch nozzle serves to direct the shielding gas to the weld pool and its diameter depends on the type of base material to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the flux cored arc welding (FCAW):",
    answers: ["The power sources for the FCAW process must be of the Constant Current type.",
    "In FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for this process.",
    "For FCAW welding, knurled rollers are recommended, so as not to overtighten the rollers, what can damage (crumple) the flux cored wire sheath.",
    "The torch nozzle serves to direct the shielding gas to the weld pool and its diameter depends on the type of base material to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the characteristics of the different types of fluxes used in Submerged Arc welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Submerged arc fluxes do not serve as sources of H2 for the weld metal.",
    "Basic fluxes are those that favour the formation of martensite in the weld, thereby improving the mechanical properties of the joint.",
    "Active fluxes are those that introduce alloying elements (such as Mn and Si) into the weld metal, but their effectiveness (percentage of introduced elements) depends on voltage and current levels.",
    "Cellulosic fluxes are used in SAW to increase penetration. "],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["the higher the welding speed, the lower the possibility of porosity and crack formation;",
    "the mechanical and chemical properties of the weld metal are mainly determined by the chemical compositions of the base metal, electrode wire and flux, but also by welding parameters.",
    "one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux is to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "the submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the submerged arc welding, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["the higher the welding speed, the lower the possibility of porosity and crack formation.",
    "one of the functions of submerged arc welding flux is to provide iron powder to increase the deposition rate;",
    "The flux protects the weld pool, provides alloying elements and elements to stabilize the arc, as well as elements for deoxidation, desulfurization and dephosphorization of the weld metal.",
    "the submerged arc welding is very suitable for making root passes without backing, but only in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding heat generation in the resistance welding process, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Resistance welding makes use mainly of the heat generated in the contact resistance between the electrodes and the surfaces of the material to be welded, which diffuses to the parts to be joined.",
    "Resistance welding is based on the generation of heat by the Peltier effect between the sheet-to-sheet contact surfaces.",
    "The heat is generated due to the resistance to the passage of current essentially along the thickness of the plates, which diffuses to the interface to be joined.",
    "The heat is generated essentially due to the resistance to the passage of current at the interface of the plates."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the flash welding (FW), it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["The FW should be applied in place of resistance upset welding (UW) when one of the materials has a high hardness.",
    "The FW process should be applied in place of UW process when the cross section of at least one of the parts is very large.",
    "The FW joining occurs exclusively by hot diffusion, not requiring the application of pressure between the parts.",
    "The excess material resulting from the applied pressure (burrs) should not be removed after welding, as those burrs guarantee the mechanical strength of the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["A shunt effect occurs when the welding current passes through the preceded spot welds in the case of multi-spot resistance welding.",
    "The greater the thickness of the sheets, the shorter the time for welding due to heating by the Joule effect.",
    "The greater the force exerted by the electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the plates.",
    "The better the electrode-plate surface contact, the longer the welding time because of less heating."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The greater the thickness of the sheets, the shorter the time for welding due to heating by the Joule effect.",
    "The name of indentation is the depression observed in a cross-section of a lap joint performed by resistance spot welding.",
    "The greater the force exerted by electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the plates.",
    "The better the electrode-plate surface contact, the longer the welding time because of less heating."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The greater the thickness of the sheets, the shorter the time for welding due to heating by the Joule effect.",
    "The greater the force exerted by electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the plates.",
    "The time counting in resistance welding processes that use alternating current is done in cycles, depending on the frequency of the electrical network.",
    "The better the electrode-plate surface contact, the longer the welding time because of less heating."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The greater the thickness of the sheets, the shorter the time for welding due to heating by the Joule effect.",
    "The greater the force exerted by electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the plates.",
    "The better the electrode-plate surface contact, the longer the welding time because of less heating.",
    "If there is a small weld spot formation and it is not possible to change the process current, the first indication is to increase the welding time to increase the spot size."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the carbon arc cutting, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The process uses a jet of inert gas to remove the molten metal.",
    "The process most commonly uses a copper-clad graphite electrode.",
    "When cutting steel, the recommended polarity is the direct current electrode negative (DCEN).",
    "The finishing of carbon arc gouging is better than plasma gouging."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the carbon arc cutting, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The process uses a jet of inert gas to remove the molten metal.",
    "When cutting steel, the recommended polarity is the direct current electrode negative (DCEN).",
    "The finishing of carbon arc gouging is better than plasma gouging.",
    "The process uses a jet of compressed air to remove the molten metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the carbon arc cutting, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["It is a very noisy process and it generates a lot of fumes.",
    "The process uses a jet of inert gas to remove the molten metal.",
    "When cutting steel, the recommended polarity is the direct current electrode negative (DCEN).",
    "The finishing of carbon arc gouging is better than plasma gouging."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the limitations of electrical resistance spot and seam welding is:",
    answers: ["Low repeatability and reliability of weld properties.",
    "Limited to overlapping joints.",
    "These are slow processes.",
    "A well-trained operator is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"As for the welding processes application methods, and respective terminologies, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is moved by the welder and the wire is fed by a motorized system.",
    "Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is fixed and the filler metal is fed by a motorized system.",
    "Adaptive control for arc length maintenance is that where the welder adapts the tip-to-work distance for each electrode diameter.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"As for the welding processes application methods, and respective terminologies, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is fixed and the filler metal is fed by a motorized system.",
    "Adaptive control for arc length maintenance is that where the welder adapts the tip-to-work distance for each electrode diameter.",
    "Manual welding is that where the entire operation (feeding filler metal, positioning the torch and its movement, others) is performed and manually controlled by the welder.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"As for the welding processes application methods, and respective terminologies, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is fixed and the filler metal is fed by a motorized system.",
    "Adaptive control for arc length maintenance is that where the welder adapts the tip-to-work distance for each electrode diameter.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator.",
    "Automatic welding is characterized by an automatic control of practically all necessary operations (a use of sensors and a possibility of programming the process clearly indicates an automatic welding process)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can be one of the reasons to increase the level of mechanization of welding processes?",
    answers: ["A lack of trained welders for manual and semi-automatic welding.",
    "To reduce manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "To optimize the choice of welding parameters.",
    "To reduce the costs of welding preparatory operations."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can be one of the reasons to increase the level of mechanization of welding processes?",
    answers: ["To reduce manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "Need to increase the welding speed.",
    "To optimize the choice of welding parameters.",
    "To reduce the costs of welding preparatory operations."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What can be one of the reasons to increase the level of mechanization of welding processes?",
    answers: ["To reduce manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "To optimize the choice of welding parameters.",
    "To reduce the health risks of welders and thus to increase welding safety.",
    "To reduce the costs of welding preparatory operations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to brazing and soldering:",
    answers: ["Whatever is the process, the wettability effect will be present.",
    "Whatever is the joint, the capillary effect will be present.",
    "The capillary effect only works in soldering, whereas in brazing the addition of metal is done by gravity.",
    "The larger the gap, the easier the capillary action and the greater the strength of the brazed/soldered joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say in relation to brazing and soldering:",
    answers: ["Whatever is the joint, the capillary effect will be present.",
    "The capillary effect increases with temperature.",
    "The capillary effect only works in soldering, whereas in brazing the addition of metal is done by gravity.",
    "The larger the gap, the easier the capillary action and the greater the strength of the brazed/soldered joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint).",
    "Multiple workpieces can be produced at once (batch processing).",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["It makes it possible to perform any type of joint (butt, angle, lapping and others).",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Great dimensional accuracy of the workpieces is ensured.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost.",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Little or no need for further finishing.",
    "Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "Allows the joining of small and difficult to access workpieces.",
    "More heat (because it is a slower process) but lower temperature is required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of fusion welding over brazing/soldering joining:",
    answers: ["An ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning it).",
    "Virtually no limitations on the size of the workpieces.",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of fusion welding over brazing/soldering joining:",
    answers: ["An ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning it).",
    "Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of fusion welding over brazing/soldering joining:",
    answers: ["An ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning it).",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas.",
    "Less preparation of the workpieces prior to welding.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of fusion welding over brazing/soldering joining:",
    answers: ["An ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning it).",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems).",
    "In most cases, it is not necessary to use a flux (deoxidizer)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of fusion welding over brazing/soldering joining:",
    answers: ["Filler metal is of lower cost.",
    "An ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning it).",
    "It is simple to be applied for joining large areas.",
    "Minor: operating time, energy consumption, modification of the metal structure, cooling stress and deformation (fewer residual stress problems)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["These are resistance welding processes: RSW; seam welding; projection welding; friction welding.",
    "The resistance seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the disc to avoid continuous stitches.",
    "Resistance welding makes use mainly of the heat generated on the resistance between the electrodes and the surfaces of the material to be welded.",
    "The dimensional variation in the direction of the sheet thickness caused by the electrode force and by the heat is called indentation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the welding definitions.",
    answers: ["Any fusion welding process can be carried out in automatic, semi-automatic or manual versions.",
    "In automatic welding the filler metal feeding and the welding head displacement are mechanized, although the positioning, actuation of the equipment and supervision are the responsibility of a welding operator.",
    "Semi-automatic welding is that where the filler metal being fed automatically by a motor, but with the translation of the heat source along the joint being performed by a non-automated machine.",
    "The MIG process can be operated either manually or semi-automatically."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the welding definitions.",
    answers: ["Any fusion welding process can be carried out in automatic, semi-automatic or manual versions.",
    "Semi-automatic welding is that where the filler metal being fed automatically by a motor, but with the translation of the heat source along the joint being performed by a non-automated machine.",
    "Manual welding is that where the entire operation (feeding filler metal, positioning the torch and its movement, others) is performed and manually controlled by the welder.",
    "The MIG process can be operated either manually or semi-automatically."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the welding definitions.",
    answers: ["Mechanized welding is that where both the filler metal feeding and the torch displacement are mechanized, and the supervision of the operation is under the responsibility of a welding operator.",
    "Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is fixed and the filler metal is fed by a motorized system.",
    "Semi-automatic welding is that with mechanization of filler metal feeding, but with translation of the heat source along the joint being performed either by the operator or by a machine.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following statement is true regarding the methods of application of a welding process and regarding respective terminologies: ",
    answers: ["Semi-automatic welding is that where the torch is fixed and the filler metal is fed by a motorized system.",
    "The MIG process can be operated either manually or semi-automatically.",
    "Manual welding is that where the entire operation (feeding filler metal, positioning the torch and its movement, others) is performed and manually controlled by the welder.",
    "A robot performs semi-automatic welding, as the trajectory is traced by manual programming of a robot operator."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Point out the proper type of primary supply for electromagnetic-type welding power sources (transformers and transformer-rectifiers) in a factory:",
    answers: ["Single-phase connection, as sources of this type do not overload the electrical network.",
    "Three-phase connection, as sources of this type charge practically almost equally all three phases of the three-phase electrical network.",
    "Single-phase connection, as it is always possible to find at least one phase with energy in the three-phase power network.",
    "Single-phase connection, as three-phase sources give a greater risk of confusing the phases when being connected to the three-phase power network."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is the heat source in flash welding?",
    answers: ["Contact resistance between adjacent surface projections that are fused by very high current densities and forcibly expelled during joining.",
    "Contact resistance between adjacent surface projections that are melted and blended by the applied pressure, without any expulsion (permanent surfaces).",
    "Resistance of the workpieces to be joined.",
    "Only by the electric arc that moves between the projections of the closely spaced surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["a slag that holds the weld pool metal in place;",
    "better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "possibility of welding thinner plates."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Without any metallurgical considerations, how to obtain a fine droplet metallic transfer when using the MMA/SMAW (111) process?",
    answers: ["Using cellulosic electrodes instead of rutilic ones.",
    "Using rutilic electrodes instead of basic ones.",
    "Increasing arc voltage.",
    "Decreasing the welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"You need to weld a carbon steel with a yield strength of 355 MPa, the carbon equivalent is 0.43 (max.) and the carbon content is 0.18 (max.). Construction is highly restricted. The plate thickness is more than 30 mm. What would your choice of covered electrode type be?",
    answers: ["Rutile type electrodes.",
    "Basic type electrodes.",
    "Acid type electrodes.",
    "Cellulosic type electrodes."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A robotic arc welding system has a contact sensor (gas nozzle sensor, for example). Which of the following tasks can it be used for?",
    answers: ["To search for the start point and also for the end point of a fillet weld.",
    "To search for the start point and also for the end point of a butt (groove) weld.",
    "\"To control the \"\"Contact Tip - Workpiece\"\" distance.\"",
    "For tracing the joint line during welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding heat generation in the spot resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The highest resistance value in the spot welding process is the resistance of the metal sheet itself.",
    "The greater the force exerted by the electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the sheets.",
    "Strictly speaking, the heat generated at the plate-to-plate interface is caused by the current passing through a contact resistance and not by the Joule effect.",
    "The generation of heat by the Joule effect along the thickness is minimal and there is no need to worry about this aspect."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding heat generation in the spot resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["The greater the thickness of the sheets, the shorter the time for welding thanks to heating by the Joule effect.",
    "The greater the force exerted by the electrodes, the greater the heating generated by the contact resistance between the sheets.",
    "The highest resistance value in the spot welding process is the contact resistance between the sheets.",
    "The better the electrode-sheet surface contact, the longer the welding time due to less heating."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"How is high energy concentration achieved in the PAW process?",
    answers: ["Using direct current with electrode in negative polarity.",
    "By constriction of the arc (nozzle-constrictor orifice).",
    "By increasing the flow rate of the plasma gas.",
    "Using a source with a high no-load voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What types of joints is aluminothermic welding best suited for?",
    answers: ["Butt joints of large thickness complex sections, in which a final molded form is demanded.",
    "Longitudinal welding in tubes.",
    "Tube welding in the manufacture of heat exchangers.",
    "Welding studs on a plate."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Among thermal cutting processes, which process produces the narrowest heat affected zone by virtue of its characteristics?",
    answers: ["Oxy fuel gas cutting.",
    "Carbon arc gouging.",
    "Plasma cutting.",
    "Laser beam cutting."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about plasma cutting:",
    answers: ["For thicknesses up to 15 mm the width of the plasma cut is greater than that obtained via oxy-fuel cutting.",
    "The main gases used are compressed air and nitrogen.",
    "Plasma cutting is a type of oxidation cutting and, during the process, the material is oxidized by the plasma jet and “blown away” using the jet itself.",
    "The finish of the cutting edges is very smooth due to the oxidation cutting principle (without melting the metal to be cut)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about plasma cutting:",
    answers: ["For thicknesses up to 15 mm the width of the plasma cut is greater than that obtained via oxy-fuel cutting.",
    "Plasma cutting is a type of oxidation cutting and, during the process, the material is oxidized by the plasma jet and “blown away” using the jet itself.",
    "Plasma cutting is a a fusion cutting process; the metal is melted by the arc and it is “blown away” by the plasma jet.",
    "The finish of the cutting edges is very smooth due to the oxidation cutting principle (without melting the metal to be cut)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say about plasma cutting:",
    answers: ["For thicknesses up to 15 mm the width of the plasma cut is greater than that obtained via oxy-fuel cutting.",
    "Plasma cutting is a type of oxidation cutting and, during the process, the material is oxidized by the plasma jet and “blown away” using the jet itself.",
    "The finish of the cutting edges is very smooth due to the oxidation cutting principle (without melting the metal to be cut).",
    "Plasma cutting can be used for all fusible metallic materials, including high-alloy steels, aluminium and its alloys, and copper and its alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding resistance welding processes, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The resistance welding type processes are: resistance spot welding; seam welding; projection welding; friction welding.",
    "The resistance seam welding is achieved by placing spaced lugs on the disc to avoid continuous stitches.",
    "Resistance welding makes use mainly of the heat generated on the resistance between the electrodes and the surfaces of the material to be welded.",
    "A weld nugget is formed by a molten metal and a heated metal at the interface between sheets to be welded."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding brazing/soldering:",
    answers: ["The soldering process can only be done manually (using a soldering iron).",
    "Brazing/soldering are favoured when using a lap-type joint (large contact surface requirement).",
    "It is not possible to join dissimilar materials.",
    "A brazing joint is achieved only by using the capillary effect."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is correct to say regarding brazing/soldering:",
    answers: ["The soldering process can only be done manually (using a soldering iron).",
    "It is not possible to join dissimilar materials.",
    "A brazed/soldered joint normally has low strength under high service temperatures.",
    "A brazing joint is achieved only by using the capillary effect."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding friction welding (FRW), the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["It is a solid-state welding process, where the coalescence is a result of the application of heat, generated by friction under pressure.",
    "It is necessary for both parts to rotate opposite each other, which is the reason for the high cost of the equipment.",
    "The process cannot be fully automated.",
    "A major limitation of the process is that it cannot be used for welding dissimilar metals."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding friction welding (FRW), the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["It is necessary for both parts to rotate opposite each other, which is the reason for the high cost of the equipment.",
    "It is autogenous welding (without filler metal).",
    "The process cannot be fully automated.",
    "A major limitation of the process is that it cannot be used for welding dissimilar metals."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding friction welding (FRW), the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["The parts to be joined come into contact with each other only after reaching the temperature of the plastic state, which facilitates joining by crushing/forging.",
    "One of the workpieces to be joined has to come into rotation.",
    "It can only be used for non-ferrous metals such as aluminium.",
    "A major limitation of the process is that it cannot be used for welding dissimilar metals."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative about TIG welding:",
    answers: ["It has low thermal efficiency, as the shielding gas dissipates a lot of electrical power, and thus, compared to other welding processes in the same current, imposes less heat on the plate.",
    "In the TIG process, unlike others welding processes, significant metal-gas reactions do not take place, producing no slag.",
    "It has low production capacity, as it is a manual process and, at most, semi-automatic.",
    "It has high thermal efficiency, as the electrical power of the arc is not spent to melt the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Tick the correct alternative about TIG welding:",
    answers: ["It has low thermal efficiency, as the shielding gas dissipates a lot of electrical power, and thus, compared to other welding processes in the same current, imposes less heat on the plate.",
    "It has low production capacity, as it is a manual process and, at most, semi-automatic.",
    "The shielding gas used in the TIG process is inert, as oxidizing gases react with the tungsten electrode.",
    "It has high thermal efficiency, as the electrical power of the arc is not spent to melt the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of resistance welding is:",
    answers: ["There is no limitation on the thickness of the sheets to be welded.",
    "High production rates.",
    "It does not pose any risk to the health of the operator (there is no arc and the working voltage is very low).",
    "It consumes little electrical energy (working voltage is too low)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of resistance welding is:",
    answers: ["Easy to mechanize or automate.",
    "There is no limitation on the thickness of the sheets to be welded.",
    "It does not pose any risk to the health of the operator (there is no arc and the working voltage is very low).",
    "It consumes little electrical energy (working voltage is too low)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of resistance welding is:",
    answers: ["There is no limitation on the thickness of the sheets to be welded.",
    "It does not pose any risk to the health of the operator (there is no arc and the working voltage is very low).",
    "It consumes little electrical energy (working voltage is too low).",
    "Operator qualification may be lower than in arc welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the advantages of resistance welding is:",
    answers: ["There is no limitation on the thickness of the sheets to be welded.",
    "It does not pose any risk to the health of the operator (there is no arc and the working voltage is very low).",
    "For some processes (eg spot welding), the influence of air on heated parts is negligible (heating from the inside to the outside), requiring no protection.",
    "It consumes little electrical energy (working voltage is too low)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which cutting process would you select, thinking about structuring a large and high production company to cut 55 mm thick A36 carbon steel sheets, with the best possible finish?",
    answers: ["Plasma cutting with compressed air (conventional).",
    "Oxy fuel gas cutting.",
    "Laser beam cutting.",
    "Plasma cutting with Ar+N2."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which cutting process would you select, thinking about structuring a small and low production company to cut 2 mm thick aluminium alloy sheets, with the best possible finish?",
    answers: ["Oxy fuel gas cutting.",
    "Plasma cutting with compressed air (conventional).",
    "Laser beam cutting.",
    "Plasma cutting with Ar+N2."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"One of the limitations of resistance spot welding, projection welding and resistance seam welding is:",
    answers: ["High investment and low portability of equipment.",
    "Low repeatability and reliability of weld properties.",
    "These are slow processes.",
    "A well-trained operator is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0"
    },
    {
    question:"According to the steel classification systems by the AISI and UNS systems, AISI 8640 and UNS G43040 steels:",
    answers: ["both have 0.4% carbon;",
    "the AISI 8640 steel has 0.4% carbon and the UNS G43040 has 0.3% carbon.",
    "the AISI 8640 steel has 0.6% carbon and the UNS G43040 has 0.4% carbon;",
    "both have 0.1% to 0.4% carbon."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO/TR 15608, quenched steels belong to the material group number:",
    answers: ["1;",
    "2;",
    "3;",
    "4."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cold welding of cast iron is done:",
    answers: ["with very low preheat;",
    "without the use of preheating;",
    "without the use of preheating during welding.",
    "with preheat applied after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Hot welding of cast iron is done:",
    answers: ["with the use of preheating;",
    "without the use of preheating;",
    "with the use of post-heating;",
    "with preheat applied after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cracks in the heat affected zone when welding thick sections of carbon steel plate can be caused by:",
    answers: ["too much preheat in the steel;",
    "a too fast weld cooling rate.",
    "use of 7016 covered electrodes type;",
    "a too low welding travel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Liquation cracking in steels occurs mainly in:",
    answers: ["the heat affected zone;",
    "fused zone;",
    "the fusion interface;",
    "the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Solidification cracking in steels occurs mainly in:",
    answers: ["the heat affected zone;",
    "fused zone;",
    "the fusion interface;",
    "the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which bonding process would probably be used where the cladding was a combination of sheets of several metal?",
    answers: ["Hot rolling.",
    "Welding.",
    "Casting.",
    "Explosive bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following properties is true of grey cast iron?",
    answers: ["Low wear resistance.",
    "Low damping capacity.",
    "Good machinability.",
    "Relatively high melting point."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"A hot-rolled steel can be distinguished from a cold-rolled steel by:",
    answers: ["bright finishing;",
    "having higher hardness;",
    "a black mill scale on its surface;",
    "being always supplied in flat sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Welding nickel and nickel alloys will generally require:",
    answers: ["procedures that are similar to that of austenitic stainless steels;",
    "procedures that are similar to that of ferritic stainless steels;",
    "procedures that are similar to that of martensitic stainless steels;",
    "procedures that are similar to that of duplex stainless steels."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following would help prevent oxidation of stainless steel surface outside the active (arc) zone?",
    answers: ["\"Tilting the torch further when using the \"\"pulling\"\" (backhand) welding technique.\"",
    "Applying a purge gas to that region of the weld joint.",
    "Increasing the gas flow rate.",
    "Adding nitrogen to the shielding gas."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Oxidation or \"\"sugaring effect\"\" on stainless steel welds is caused by:\"",
    answers: ["insufficient shielding.",
    "high heat input.",
    "too low welding travel.",
    "too high current."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of preheating will:",
    answers: ["produce a higher hardness in the heat affected zone;",
    "increase the tendency of martensite formation in the heat affected zone;",
    "reduce the heat affected zone;",
    "decrease the cooling rate."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of preheating will:",
    answers: ["produce a higher hardness in the heat affected zone;",
    "reduce the heat affected zone;",
    "reduce the tendency of martensite formation in the heat affected zone;",
    "increase the tendency of martensite formation in the heat affected zone."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of preheating will:",
    answers: ["reduce the heat affected zone;",
    "reduce hardness in the heat affected zone;",
    "produce higher hardness in the heat affected zone; ",
    "increase the tendency of martensite formation in the heat affected zone."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of preheating will:",
    answers: ["increase the heat affected zone;",
    "reduce the heat affected zone;",
    "increase the tendency of martensite formation in the heat affected zone;",
    "produce higher hardness in the heat affected zone."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the main purpose of preheating in welding?",
    answers: ["To increase welding production efficiency (the melting rate).",
    "To reduce distortion.",
    "To reduce the heat affected zone.",
    "To reduce the cooling rate of the welded joint."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the main purpose of preheating in welding?",
    answers: ["To increase welding production efficiency (the melting rate).",
    "To reduce distortion.",
    "To reduce the heat affected zone.",
    "To reduce the risk of cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The post-heating heat treatment of a welded steel joint:",
    answers: ["allows the diffusion of O2 to the external environment, reducing the residual O2 content;",
    "allows the diffusion of H2 to the external environment, reducing the residual H2 content;",
    "is applied at temperatures between 200 and 300 °C for periods never exceeding 10 min to avoid plastic deformation;",
    "allows the dissolution of heat affected zone inclusions, preventing liquation cracks."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In bridge construction, one of the advantages of high strength steels over common structural steels is:",
    answers: ["easier corrosion protection;",
    "high Young's modulus;",
    "high elongation;",
    "high yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In bridge construction, one of the advantages of high strength steels over common structural steels is:",
    answers: ["easier corrosion protection;",
    "high Young's modulus;",
    "high elongation;",
    "low ductile-brittle transition temperature."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the factor influencing the coarsening grains in welded joints of steels?",
    answers: ["The exchange of direct current for alternating current.",
    "The presence of diffusible H2.",
    "A preheat.",
    "An increase in the number of passes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the factor influencing the coarsening grains in welded joints of steels?",
    answers: ["The exchange of direct current for alternating current.",
    "The presence of diffusible H2.",
    "A higher heat input.",
    "An increase in the number of passes."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following alloys are most susceptible to hydrogen induced embrittlement?",
    answers: ["0.38% carbon steel.",
    "18Cr 8Ni stainless steel.",
    "Nb-V micro alloyed steel.",
    "9Cr-2Mo steel with aditions of Nb e V."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following alloys are most susceptible to hydrogen induced embrittlement?",
    answers: ["2¼Cr 1Mo low alloy steel.",
    "18Cr 8Ni stainless steel.",
    "Nb-V micro alloyed steel.",
    "9Cr-2Mo steel with aditions of Nb e V."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding post-heating of a steel welded joint, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["It aims to reduce the cooling rate in the welded region, to minimize fragile microstructures formation.",
    "It allows the diffusion of H2 to the external environment, reducing the residual H2 content;",
    "It allows the dissolution of heat affested zone inclusions, preventing liquation cracks.",
    "It allows to minimize the formation of fragile microstructures in the HAZ, preventing H2 cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding preheating of a steel welded joint, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["It aims to reduce the cooling rate in the welded region, to minimize fragile microstructures formation.",
    "It allows the diffusion of H2 to the external environment, reducing the residual H2 content;",
    "It allows the dissolution of heat affested zone inclusions, preventing liquation cracks.",
    "It allows faster cooling of the HAZ region, preventing H2 cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be taken into account to determine the preheat temperature when welding C-Mn steel?",
    answers: ["Groove type.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Phosphor and sulphur content.",
    "Heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be taken into account to determine the preheat temperature when welding C-Mn steel?",
    answers: ["Groove type.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Phosphor and sulphur content.",
    "Carbon equivalent."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be taken into account to determine the preheat temperature when welding C-Mn steel?",
    answers: ["Groove type.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Phosphor and sulphur content.",
    "Joint thickness."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Alloyed steels with 3-9% Ni are primarily used for their properties:",
    answers: ["at elevated temperatures (i.e., creep resistance)",
    "at climatic conditions with temperatures ranging from very low to very high;",
    "at service temperatures below - 60 °C;",
    "where high resistance to corrosion is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Alloyed steels with 3-9% Ni are primarily used for their properties:",
    answers: ["at elevated temperatures (i.e., creep resistance)",
    "at climatic conditions with temperatures ranging from very low to very high;",
    "at very low temperatures (i.e., cryogenic applications);",
    "where high resistance to corrosion is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following temperature ranges is generally used for the post weld stress relieving of 0.25% C steel weldments?",
    answers: ["420 - 540 °C.",
    "600 - 650 °C.",
    "700 - 820 °C.",
    "870 - 980 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding C/Mn-steel, the hydrogen cracks normally appear in:",
    answers: ["weld metal;",
    "heat affected zone (HAZ);",
    "base metal outside of HAZ;",
    "\"weld interface \"\"Fusion zone - HAZ\"\".\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The basic property of steel working in very low temperature is:",
    answers: ["resistance to brittle cracking;",
    "strength;",
    "hardness;",
    "the lack to ageing susceptibility."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The corrosion inhibitors are:",
    answers: ["the substances that can reduce the rate of corrosion when added to a given environment in a certain amount together with a catalyzer;",
    "the substances that can reduce the corrosion rate of a material when added to that material in a determined amount;",
    "the substances that can reduce the corrosion rate of a material when added to that material in a determined amount together with a catalyzer;",
    "the substances which reduce the corrosion rate when added, even in small concentration, to a corrosive environment."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The weldability of thick cast iron gives least problems when using:",
    answers: ["ferritic grey cast iron;",
    "ordinary grey cast iron;",
    "ferritic nodular cast iron;",
    "white malleable cast iron."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is pure argon shielding gas not appropriate for welding of non-alloy steel?",
    answers: ["The heat input is too low.",
    "This gas is too expensive.",
    "The arc becomes unstable.",
    "It causes a lot of spatter."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The addition of helium in a shielding gas for welding of aluminium:",
    answers: ["gives a deeper penetration;",
    "gives less spatter;",
    "reduces the arc voltage;",
    "reduces the heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Nickel alloy butt joint configurations commonly are:",
    answers: ["the same as for mild steels;",
    "the same as for stainless steels;",
    "with narrower groove angle than for mild steels;",
    "with wider groove angle than for mild steels."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Inconel is often used for:",
    answers: ["cold temperature applications;",
    "high temperature applications;",
    "high impact applications;",
    "abrasive wear resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The addition of over 6% nickel to stainless steels will always:",
    answers: ["increase corrosion resistance;",
    "increase abrasive wear resistance;",
    "increase surface hardness;",
    "reduce hot cracking in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The addition of over 6% nickel to stainless steels will always:",
    answers: ["increase impact resistance at lower temperatures;",
    "increase abrasive wear resistance;",
    "increase surface hardness;",
    "reduce hot cracking in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The addition of over 6% nickel to stainless steels will always:",
    answers: ["improve high temperature performance;",
    "increase abrasive wear resistance;",
    "increase surface hardness;",
    "reduce hot cracking in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The biggest problem when welding martensitic stainless steels is:",
    answers: ["grain growth in the HAZ;",
    "carbide precipitation in the HAZ;",
    "cracking in the HAZ;",
    "distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Between what temperatures might carbide precipitation occur when welding austenitic stainless steels?",
    answers: ["200 °C to 400 °C.",
    "300 °C to 500 °C.",
    "400 °C to 700 °C.",
    "450 °C to 850 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding austenitic stainless steels, carbide precipitation can be prevented by:",
    answers: ["maintaining the interpass temperature high enough (500 °C to 600 °C);",
    "applying a post heating (500 °C to 600 °C) during, at least, 1 hour;",
    "reducing travel speed;",
    "limiting the carbon level in the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding austenitic stainless steels, carbide precipitation can be prevented by:",
    answers: ["maintaining the interpass temperature high enough (500 °C to 600 °C);",
    "applying a post heating (500 °C to 600 °C) during, at least, 1 hour;",
    "reducing travel speed;",
    "addition of stabilizers."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding austenitic stainless steels, carbide precipitation can be prevented by:",
    answers: ["maintaining the interpass temperature high enough (500 °C to 600 °C);",
    "applying a post heating (500 °C to 600 °C) during, at least, 1 hour;",
    "reducing travel speed;",
    "using as low a heat input as practical."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding austenitic stainless steels, carbide precipitation can be prevented by:",
    answers: ["maintaining the interpass temperature high enough (500 °C to 600 °C);",
    "applying a post heating (500 °C to 600 °C) during, at least, 1 hour;",
    "reducing travel speed;",
    "controlled rapid cooling."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"If an age precipitation hardening nickel alloy is to be welded, what type of filler metal should be selected?",
    answers: ["One with high ductility.",
    "One that is also hardened by precipitation. ",
    "One that is hardened by solid solution. ",
    "One with very low carbon content."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When MIG/MAG welding (GMAW) nickel alloys, which shielding gas is normally used?",
    answers: ["CO2.",
    "Mixture argon + CO2.",
    "Mixture argon + O2.",
    "Pure argon or a mixture argon + helium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Where are clad materials used?",
    answers: ["When abrasion resistance is required.",
    "In cryogenic applications.",
    "For lightweight structures.",
    "When high ductility is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Where are clad materials used?",
    answers: ["In high heat applications.",
    "In cryogenic applications.",
    "For lightweight structures.",
    "When high ductility is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Where are clad materials used?",
    answers: ["When corrosion resistance is required.",
    "In cryogenic applications.",
    "For lightweight structures.",
    "When high ductility is needed."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"Regarding the effect of a weld on the fracture performance of a component, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the residual stresses of a weld tend to play an important role in the nucleation and propagation of cracks in brittle fracture;",
    "a welded joint is a discontinuity and it makes it possible to stop (“arrest”) the propagation of cracks;",
    "A well-made weld with reinforcement within the limits prescribed by the standard does not imply any deterioration in its resistance to fracture.",
    "the residual stresses of a weld tend to play a key role in the case of a component failure due to overload."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the effect of a weld on the fracture performance of a component, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["discontinuities, such as lack of fusion and lack of penetration, facilitate the nucleation of cracks;",
    "a welded joint is a discontinuity and it makes it possible to stop (“arrest”) the propagation of cracks;",
    "A well-made weld with reinforcement within the limits prescribed by the standard does not imply any deterioration in its resistance to fracture.",
    "the residual stresses of a weld tend to play a key role in the case of a component failure due to overload."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor is not considered in the fatigue resistance calculation of most standards, but it can cause changes in the S-N curves:",
    answers: ["groove preparation type of the welded joint;",
    "backhand or forehand welding technique;",
    "welding position;",
    "plate thickness."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor is not considered in the fatigue resistance calculation of most standards, but it can cause changes in the S-N curves:",
    answers: ["groove preparation type of the welded joint;",
    "backhand or forehand welding technique;",
    "welding position;",
    "environment effect (eg aggressive environments)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor is not considered in the fatigue resistance calculation of most standards, but it can cause changes in the S-N curves:",
    answers: ["groove preparation type of the welded joint;",
    "backhand or forehand welding technique;",
    "welding position;",
    "effect of joint profile improvement techniques (peening, weld toe machining, TIG dressing, ...)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"This factor is not considered in the fatigue resistance calculation of most standards, but it can cause changes in the S-N curves:",
    answers: ["groove preparation type of the welded joint;",
    "backhand or forehand welding technique;",
    "welding position;",
    "the frequency at which the cycles are applied."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of fillet welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and leg length;",
    "The effective length of the fillet weld does not include the weld start and end regions;",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the weld toe;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the transverse direction of the fillet weld is more important than in the longitudinal direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of fillet welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and leg length;",
    "The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and effective length of the weld;",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the weld toe;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the transverse direction of the fillet weld is more important than in the longitudinal direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of fillet welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and leg length;",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the outer side of the inscribed triangle (for the right triangle it is the hypotenuse);",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the weld toe;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the transverse direction of the fillet weld is more important than in the longitudinal direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of fillet welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and leg length;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the longitudinal direction of the fillet weld is important;",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the weld toe;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the transverse direction of the fillet weld is more important than in the longitudinal direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of fillet welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective area is calculated as the product of effective throat and leg length;",
    "EUROCODE 3 specifies that residual stresses need not be taken into account when evaluating the fillet weld strength;",
    "The effective throat is calculated as the distance between the root of the weld and the weld toe;",
    "According to EUROCODE 3, the shear stress in the transverse direction of the fillet weld is more important than in the longitudinal direction;"],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In general terms, fatigue life depends on:",
    answers: ["the type of loading;",
    "welding process used if MIG/MAG or MMA (SMAW);",
    "the type of shielding gas used;",
    "the size of the structure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In general terms, fatigue life depends on:",
    answers: ["the surface condition;",
    "the welding process used if MIG/MAG or MMA (SMAW);",
    "the type of shielding gas used;",
    "the size of the structure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In general terms, fatigue life depends on:",
    answers: ["the joint design;",
    "the welding process used if MIG/MAG or MMA (SMAW);",
    "the type of shielding gas used;",
    "the size of the structure."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The load-bearing section of a butt weld is determined calculating:",
    answers: ["the product of the thickness of the joint thinnest member and its total length from the beginning to the end of the weld",
    "the product of the thickness of the joint thickest member and its length discounting the beginning and end of the weld",
    "the product of the thickness of the joint thinnest member and its effective length, discounting the beginning and end of the weld",
    "the product of weld joint thickness and its length. Weld surface and root reinforcements are taken into account"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of butt welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the greatest thickness of the connected plates;",
    "The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the smallest thickness of the connected plates plus the height of the reinforcement;",
    "The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the smallest thickness of the connected plates plus the surface and root reinforcement heights;",
    "Butt welds are generally more efficient than fillet welds of the same strength as they require less deposited metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"When selecting the size of butt welds, it is truth that:",
    answers: ["The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the greatest thickness of the connected plates;",
    "The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the smallest thickness of the connected plates plus the height of the reinforcement;",
    "The effective thickness of a full penetration butt weld is the smallest thickness of the connected plates plus the surface and root reinforcement heights;",
    "Full penetration butt welds are designed to have the same mechanical strength, in effective area, as the joint members"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"A welded structure that has been correctly sized to withstand static loading, but is under cyclic loading, can collapse due to:",
    answers: ["outflow failure;",
    "creep failure;",
    "fatigue failure;",
    "buckling failure."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9000, welding is a:",
    answers: ["combined process;",
    "critical process;",
    "special process;",
    "quality process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the highest open circuit voltage (r.m.s. value) allowed for alternating current welding for environment with increased hazard of electric shock (as per IEC-60974-1)?",
    answers: ["48 V",
    "60 V",
    "80 V",
    "113 V"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Flame straightening is most frequently used for:",
    answers: ["thin aluminium alloys;",
    "non-alloyed steel;",
    "high-alloyed steel;",
    "thin cast iron sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding aluminium, how can distortion be minimised?",
    answers: ["By increasing the welding current.",
    "By using welding fixtures.",
    "By using helium as shielding gas.",
    "Applying hammering after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the elaboration and the necessity to use standards, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["A welding standard must be applied when, for example, within a project the application of a welding process is contractually governed by that standard;",
    "Only welding engineers can develop welding standards;",
    "The application of a standard does not increase the initial cost of a work, on the contrary, it reduces production costs;",
    "The application of a standard does not increase the initial cost of a work, as qualified personnel and procedures, as well as calibrated equipment, among others, are not mandatory."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"How will preheat reduce distortion?",
    answers: ["By producing uniform expansion and contraction.",
    "By retarding the quench rate of the heat affected zone.",
    "By allowing the use of faster welding speeds.",
    "By reducing the welding time."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a technique used to minimize the risk of component failure due to internal stresses generated by the welding process in structural steels?",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Slow heating after welding, to a temperature above the steel transformation temperature, for a period of time, followed by slow cooling;",
    "Heat treatment for stress relief, at temperatures between 600 and 700 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a “good practice” in a stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels to:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece immediately after welding to 200 - 300 °C, without letting the weld cool down;",
    "Heat and cool the workpiece slowly so that it does not create a considerable temperature gradient."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a “good practice” in a stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels to:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Slow heating after welding, to a temperature above the steel transformation temperature, for a period of time, followed by slow cooling;",
    "Keep the jigs or fasteners applied during heat treatment to avoid distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is a “good practice” in a stress relieving heat treatment of low-alloy carbon steels to:",
    answers: ["Heat the workpiece quickly so that it does not reduce the hardness of the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece slowly so as not to harden the material;",
    "Heat the workpiece immediately after welding to 200 - 300 °C, without letting the weld cool down;",
    "Heat slowly after welding, to a temperature below the transformation temperature of the steel, for a period of time, followed by slow cooling."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To measure the preheating temperature, you can use:",
    answers: ["Tactile probing;",
    "Laser temperature measurement.",
    "Contact thermometers;",
    "Calorimeter."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To measure the preheating temperature, you can use:",
    answers: ["Tactile probing;",
    "Laser temperature measurement.",
    "Thermocouples;",
    "Calorimeter."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"To measure the preheating temperature, you can use:",
    answers: ["Tactile probing;",
    "Laser temperature measurement.",
    "Temperature indicating sticks;",
    "Calorimeter."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What are the main factors that influence welding costs?",
    answers: ["Consumables, and operator/welder training expenses.",
    "Consumables, equipment and labour.",
    "Cost of electricity, equipment and safety material.",
    "Equipment, expenses with the preparation and fixing of the plates, as well as expenses with post cleaning operations."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the option that represents direct costs of welding and thermal cutting:",
    answers: ["Consumables, equipment and expenses with lighting and ventilation;",
    "Consumables, equipment and labour;",
    "Cost of electricity, equipment and safety material;",
    "Equipment, expenses with the preparation and fixing of the plates, as well as expenses with post cleaning operations."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Liquid Penetrant Test, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["It is applied to detect superficial and internal cracks in the material;",
    "The penetrant can be applied by spray and brush or by immersion;",
    "Can be applied at any temperature;",
    "A good developer should spread the penetrant."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which factor is very important in industrial competitiveness in the field of welding?",
    answers: ["Type of welding process used.",
    "Use of WPSs.",
    "Use of Standards.",
    "Costs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Before starting a welding project with quality control, it is necessary for the Welding Engineer to prepare several documents, but the 1st document to be generated is:",
    answers: ["Welder Qualification Record (WQR);",
    "Welding Execution and Inspection Instruction (WEII);",
    "Welding Procedure Specification (WPS);",
    "Inspection Report (IR)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding discontinuities and defects, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["that discontinuity acceptance criteria may change depending on the quality level that must be defined prior to construction, as per ISO 5817;",
    "that discontinuities originate basically from welding as the other manufacturing processes (rolling, machining, ...) are much less likely to generate discontinuities;",
    "what should be demanded is zero discontinuity, even if such determination leads to slightly higher costs;",
    "that the most adequate method of discontinuities identification is a volumetric one (ultrasonic testing or radiography)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of positioners, fixtures and jigs can offer:",
    answers: ["a possibility of producing imperfections-free welds;",
    "a possibility of reducing thermal stresses in the welded joint;",
    "a possibility to use a greater number of welders for the same construction being welded;",
    "a possibility of reducing the welding time by using the PA position;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of positioners, fixtures and jigs can offer:",
    answers: ["a possibility of producing imperfections-free welds;",
    "a possibility of reducing thermal stresses in the welded joint;",
    "a possibility to use a greater number of welders for the same construction being welded;",
    "a possibility of reducing the risk of generating defects by using the PA position;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of positioners, fixtures and jigs can offer:",
    answers: ["a possibility of producing imperfections-free welds;",
    "a possibility of reducing thermal stresses in the welded joint;",
    "a possibility to use a greater number of welders for the same construction being welded;",
    "a possibility to use welders qualified for the simplest welding position, namely the PA position."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following must be performed in order to protect the welding operator during intensive resistance spot welding of zinc coated plates?",
    answers: ["To wear a gas mask.",
    "Adequate ventilation and fume extraction must be provided.",
    "To clean the electrodes more often to avoid zinc build-up.",
    "To clean the zinc coating before welding, as it is not possible to joint galvanized sheets by resistance spot welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The method of detection of internal discontinuities of material by Ultrasonic waves is based on:",
    answers: ["Measurement of the power of the sent ultrasonic signal and of the power of its echo reflected from the discontinuity.",
    "Measurement of the frequency difference of the sent ultrasonic signal and of its echo reflected from the discontinuity.",
    "Propagation of ultrasonic waves in material and the capture of their reflection from the boundary surface of the two media (the material and the discontinuity).",
    "Measurement of the time between sending the ultrasonic waves into the material and capturing their reflection from the boundary surface of the two media (the material and the discontinuity)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welding coordination personnel is qualified according to: ",
    answers: ["ISO 14731;",
    "ISO 14732;",
    "ISO 15607;",
    "ISO 9606."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Welding operators are qualified according to:",
    answers: ["ISO 14731;",
    "ISO 14732;",
    "ISO 15607;",
    "ISO 9606."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the definitions of Quality:",
    answers: ["It is a special feature of a product having customer's satisfaction;",
    "It is a special feature of the products that is valid forever;",
    "It is when a product has a long shelf life;",
    "Quality product has no defects and has a long service life."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the definitions of Quality:",
    answers: ["it is a property of the product that is suitable to fulfil requirements defined by the customer's specification;",
    "It is a special feature of the products that is valid forever;",
    "It is when a product has a long shelf life;",
    "Quality product has no defects and has a long service life."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the magnetic particle suspension fluids is:",
    answers: ["a clear glue (you need to see the particles!);",
    "a transparent industrial gelatine;",
    "a transparent foam;",
    "water."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the magnetic particle suspension fluids is:",
    answers: ["a clear glue (you need to see the particles!)",
    "a transparent industrial gelatine;",
    "a transparent foam;",
    "kerosene."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the magnetic particle suspension fluids is:",
    answers: ["a clear glue (you need to see the particles!);",
    "a transparent industrial gelatine;",
    "a transparent foam;",
    "oil."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 T BW W11 RB t10 D200 H-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, SMAW/MMA welding, tube of 20 cm diameter, butt weld, stainless steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MAG welding, tube of 20 cm diameter, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, tube of 200 mm diameter, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, tube of 20 cm diameter, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 T BW W11 RB t10 D200 H-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, rutile-basic covered electrode, material thickness = 10 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld without filler metal, material thickness = 10 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld without filler metal, material thickness = 10 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, rutile covered electrode, material thickness = 10 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 T BW W11 RB t10 D200 H-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined angle of 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe downwards position with the axis inclined at 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined at 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe with the axis inclined at 45 degrees, overhead welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 111 T BW W11 RB t10 D200 H-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 nm t03 D20 H-L030 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, Oxyacetylene welding, pipe of 2 cm diameter, butt weld, carbon steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MIG welding, plate, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, pipe of 20 mm diameter, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plate, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 nm t03 D20 H-L030 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld without fillet metal, material thickness = 3 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld with filler metal, material thickness = 3 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld without filler metal, material thickness = 3 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld with filler metal, material thickness = 3 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 nm t03 D20 H-L030 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined angle of 30 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe downwards position with the axis inclined at 30 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined at 30 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe with the axis inclined at 30 degrees, overhead welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 nm t03 D20 H-L030 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 wm t02 D20 J-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, Oxyacetylene welding, pipe of 2 cm diameter, butt weld, carbon steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, MIG welding, plate, butt weld, fine-grain structural steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, pipe of 20 mm diameter, butt weld, non-alloy steel.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, TIG welding, plate, fillet weld, non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 wm t02 D20 J-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld with fillet metal, material thickness = 2 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld without filler metal, material thickness = 2 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld without filler metal, material thickness = 2 mm.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld with filler metal, material thickness = 2 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 wm t02 D20 J-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe downwards position with the axis inclined angle of 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined at 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, pipe upwards position with the axis inclined angle of 45 degrees.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, pipe with the axis inclined at 45 degrees, overhead welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following alternatives correctly explains some details of the \"\"ISO 9606-1 311 T BW W01 wm t02 D20 J-L045 ss nb\"\" designation?\"",
    answers: ["International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, butt weld, single side welding, with backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, welding from both sides, without backing.",
    "International standard for welder qualification, fillet weld, single side welding, without backing."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the main constituent of the fume produced when welding mild steel?",
    answers: ["Carbon oxides.",
    "Chromium oxides.",
    "Manganese oxides.",
    "Iron oxides."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"}];
    
    
    